Guide to the John "The Cop" Quigley Collection MC.100
New York University Archives
John "The Cop" Quigley Collection
1935-1937
New York University Archives
Oscar Rose, Secretary of the Committee on Publication; member of the NYU Arts and Engineering Alumni Association
MC.100
248
0.5 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box
This collection contains correspondence and questionnaires regarding life at the University Heights campus of New York University and John "the Cop" Quigley (1872-1943), the campus' senior patrolman and a popular figure at the school. John Quigley was an officer at the University Heights campus for 47 years. The secretary of the Committee on Publication, Oscar Rose, elicited anecdotes, stories, and photographs from alumnus about Quigley in preparation for Forty Years of John the Cop, a book that celebrated Quigley's fortieth anniversary at the University Heights campus.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Daniel Quilty, Director of Athletics. The accession number associated with this collection is 82.022.
Arrangement
Original order was preserved. The materials in this collection do not appear to be arranged chronologically. Each respondent or correspondent has been given a folder.
Historical note
John Quigley (1872-1943), also known as "John the Cop," was the senior patrolman of the University Heights campus of New York University. Quigley immigrated to the United States from Tipperary, Ireland in 1892. He began working at NYU's University Heights campus in 1896 and served as the senior patrolman of the campus for 47 years. Quigley was a popular and memorable figure on campus.
In 1935, Oscar Rose, the Secretary of the Committee on Publication and a member of the New York University Arts and Engineering Alumni Association, began compiling information for John Quigley's biography, Forty Years of John the Cop. Rose's general letter to University Heights alumni is included in the collection.
The University Heights campus, located in the Bronx, was a male-only undergraduate campus. It was opened in the late nineteenth-century and sold in 1973.
Scope and Contents
This collection is comprised of correspondence and questionnaires collected by Oscar Rose between 1935 and 1938 for a proposed biography of John ""the Cop" Quigley. Quigley was a senior patrolman and guardian of the University Heights campus. The correspondence and questionnaires pertain to both John Quigley and life at the University Heights campus of New York University.
Correspondence.; Questionnaires.; John Quigley, 1872-1943; New York University. University Heights
- James Dalton - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174207 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- NYU Bureau of Public Information - Announcement of John Quigley's death, July 20, 1943; 174217 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Edward B. Willing - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174218 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- E. H. Hamilton - Letter and Anecdotes about John Quigley, July 16, 1935; 174219 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Leonard Eckman - Letter to Oscar Rose, June 12, 1935; 174220 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- W. O. Partisch - Letter and Questionnaire, June 26, 1935; 174221 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- H. F. Watson - Excerpts from an N.Y.U. Diary and Letter to Oscar Rose, October 4, 1935; 174222 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Irving E. Mansback - Anecdotes related to John Quigley and Letter to Oscar Rose, April 22, 1935; 174223 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- John E. Longua - Letter to Oscar Rose, June 7, 1935; 174224 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Irving E. Mansback - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174225 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Sidney Feildrey - Letter to Oscar Rose, June 7, 1935; 174226 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Freeman Woodbridge - Letter to Oscar Rose, June 7, 1935; 174227 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- E. H. Hamilton - Letter to Oscar Rose, July 10. 1935; 174228 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Bill Luasha - Questionnaire and Letter to Oscar Rose, June 6, 1935; 174229 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- W. Elstad - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174230 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Chas D. Humphey - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174231 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Charles A. Tonsor - Letter to Oscar Rose, January 21, 1935; 174232 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Joe Hickey - Letter to Oscar Rose, July 30, 1935; 174233 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Richard A. Lynch Jr. - Letter to Oscar Rose, July 30, 1935; 174234 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Rudolph Macy - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174235 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- A. W. Odgen - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174236 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- T. Jiel - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174237 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Benjamin A. Ross - Letter to Oscar Rose, May 5, 1936; 174238 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Anon. - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174239 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Edward J. McKary - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174240 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Anon. - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174241 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- John M. Laughran - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174242 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Robert S. Whightman - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174243 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Lindorf - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174244 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Theodore A. Distler - Letter to Oscar Rose, June 21, 1935; 174245 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Hoyt Hostutter - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174246 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Arthur J. O'dea - Letter to Oscar Rose, July 11, 1935; 174247 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Richard D. Pilieasteru - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174248 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Harold Lenz - Questionnaire, June 11, 1935; 174249 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Dr. Frank J. Goff - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174250 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Seymour Male - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174251 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Charles P. Murphy - Letter to Lawrence Lang, July 10, 1935; 174252 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Oscar Rose - Letter to Alumnus, c. 1935; 174253 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- C. A. Bill - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174254 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- H. F. Watson - Letter to Oscar Rose and Questionnaire, June 15, 1935; 174255 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Munro G. Rieser - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174256 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Donald F. Brown - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174257 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- J. F. Rockwatt - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174258 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Julian N. Henriques - Questionaire and Letter, June 17, 1935; 174259 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Dr. S. Bernard Wortis - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174260 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Dr. George A. Simons - Questionnaire and Pamphlets, c. 1935; 174261 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Erwin H. Hamilton - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174262 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Charles P. Murphy - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174263 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Stanley Kenward - Questionnaire and Photographs, c. 1935; 174264 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Erwin H. Hamilton - Letter to Oscar Rose and Anecdotes, August 21, 1935; 174265 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Jules W. Goldschmidt - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174266 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Anon. - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174267 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Harold H. Ball - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174268 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Philip Finkelstein - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174269 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- D. H. Elineweisch - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174270 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- M. L. Bettcher - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174271 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Ernest Larson - Letter to Oscar Rose and Questionnaire, June 11, 1935; 174272 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Richard A. Lynch, Jr. - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174273 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Joseph W. Roe - Letter to Oscar Rose and Questionnaire, June 6, 1935; 174274 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- John P. Phillips - Letter to Oscar Rose and Questionnaire, June 18, 1935; 174275 (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Walter S. L. Cleverdon - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174276 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- George J. Viertel - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174277 (Box 1, Folder 62)
- C. Raymond Kramer - Letter to Oscar Rose and Questionnaire, June 11, 1935; 174278 (Box 1, Folder 63)
- A. L. Borton - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174279 (Box 1, Folder 64)
- Sam M. Hollander - Letter to Oscar Rose, July 10, 1935; 174280 (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Cayuga Press - Letter to Oscar Rose, February 15, 1935; 174281 (Box 1, Folder 66)
- Ben Ross - Letter to Oscar Rose, January 11, 1938; 174282 (Box 1, Folder 67)
- Sam M. Hollander - Letter to Oscar Rose, August 27, 1937; 174283 (Box 1, Folder 68)
- Eugene R. Canudo - Letter to Oscar Rose, January 6, 1933; 174284 (Box 1, Folder 69)
- Ben Ross - Letter to Oscar Rose, March 28, 1935; 174285 (Box 1, Folder 70)
- Arthur H. Nason - Letter to Oscar Rose and Questionnaire, June 6, 1935; 174286 (Box 1, Folder 71)
- Stanley Harte - Questionnaire, c. 1935; 174287 (Box 1, Folder 72)
- Sam M. Hollander - Letter to Oscar Rose, June 3, 1935; 174288 (Box 1, Folder 73)
- Deems Taylor - Letter to Oscar Rose, October 16, 1935; 174289 (Box 1, Folder 74)